Anyone in the room thought about sex today?
هل يوجد اي فكر في الجنس اليوم؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Yeah, you did.
نعم , أنت فعلت.
Thank you for putting your hand up over there.
شكرًا لرفع ايديكم هنالك.
Well, I'm here to provide you with
حسنًا انا هنا كي اقدم لكم
some biological validation
بعض الحقائق من الأحياء
for your sordid daydreams.
لأحلام يقظتكم السيئة
I'm here to tell you a few things
أنا هنا لكي اخبركم بعض الأشياء
that you might not have known about wild sex.
التي لربما لم تعرفوها عن الجنس في البرية.
Now, when humans think about sex,
الان عندما يفكر الناس في الجنس
male and female forms
نوعيه الذكوري والأنثوي
are generally what come to mind,
غالبًا مايخطر على البال.
but for many millions of years,
لكن لملاين السنين
such specific categories didn't even exist.
مثل هذه الفئات لم تتواجد.
Sex was a mere fusion of bodies
الجنس كان مجرد انصهار للأجسام
or a trickle of DNA
او تقطر لالـ (دي ان اي)
shared between two or more beings.
يتشاركه اثنان او أكثر من كائن.
It wasn't until about 500 million years ago
لم يكن حتى 500 مليون عام فيما مضى
that we start to see structures akin to a penis
حتى بدأنا نرى تراكيب مماثلة للقضيب
or a thing that gives DNA out,
او اي شيء ينشر الـ (دي ان اي)
and a vagina, something that receives it.
و في بعض الأحيان مهبل يستقبله
Now invariably, you're probably thinking about
الان محتمل انكم تفكرون
what belongs to our own species,
مالذي ينتمي لفصيلتنا
these very familiar structures,
هذه اعضاء مألوفة
but the diversity that we see in sexual structures
لكن التنوع الذي نراه في التراكيب الجنسية
in the animal kingdom that has evolved
في مملكة الحيوان التي تطورت
in response to the multitude of factors
كنتيجة للعديد من العوامل
surrounding reproduction
المحيطة بالتكاثر
is pretty mind-blowing.
مذهل للغاية
Penile diversity is especially profuse.
التنوع القضيبي تحديدًا متعدد.
So this is a paper nautilus.
إذن هذه بيبر نوتيلس ( حيوان البحار المتنقل الورقي)
It's a close relative of squid and octopus,
هي قريبة من الحبار والإخطبوط
and males have a hectocotylus.
لدى الذكور هيكتوكوتيلاس ( ذو المئة كويب)
Just what is a hectocotylus?
إذن ماهو الهيكتوكوتيلاس (ذو المئة كويب)؟
A detachable, swimming penis.
هو قضيب سابح يمكن فصله
It leaves the [body of the male],
يترك جسم الذكر
finds the female through pheromonal cues in the water,
ليبحث عن الأنثى من خلال الفيرمونات في الماء
attaches itself to her body
يتعلق بجسدها
and deposits the sperm.
ثم يخزن الحيوانات المنوية.
For many decades, biologists actually felt
لعدة عقود اعتقد علماء الأحياء ان
that the hectocotylus was a separate organism altogether.
(ذو المئة كويب) كائن قائم بذاته.
Now, the tapir is a mammal from South America.
الان التابير من ثديات امريكا الجنوبية
And the tapir has a prehensile penis.
و له قضيب يقدر على المسك
It actually has a level of dexterity in its penis
في الحقيقة لقضيبة مستوى من المهارة
much akin to what we have with our hands.
مماثلة لمهارة اليد
And it uses this dexterity
وهو يستخدم هذه المهارة
to bypass the vagina altogether
حتى يتعدى المهبل
and deposit sperm directly into the female's uterus,
ويخزن الحيوانات المنوية مباشرة في الرحم.
not to mention it's a pretty good size.
من دون ذكر حجمه الجيد
The biggest penis in the animal kingdom,
اكبر قضيب في مملكة الحيوان
however, is not that of the tapir.
لا يمتلكه التابير.
The biggest penis-to-body-size ratio
اكبر قضيب مقارنة بنسبة الجسد إلى القضيب
in the animal kingdom actually belongs
في مملكة الحيوانات ينتمى إلى
to the meager beach barnacle,
إلى البرنقيل الإوز
and this video is actually showing you
وهذا الشريط حقيقة يريكم
what the human penis would look like
شكل قضيب الإنسان
if it were the same size as that of a barnacle.
إذا كان له نفس حجم قضيب البرنقيل
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Mm-hm. (Laughter)
امم اهمم (ضحك)
So with all of this diversity in structure,
إذن بسبب كل هذا التنوع في التركيب
one might think, then, that penises
بإمكان الشخص ان يظن ان القضائب
are fitting neatly into vaginas all over the place
تشغل حيزً المهبل بالكامل.
for the purposes of successful reproduction.
لغرض تكاثر ناجح
Simply insert part A into slot B,
ببساطة ادخل أ في النقطة ب
and we should all be good to go.
وينبغي لنا جميعًا ان نكون على مايرام.
But of course, that doesn't exactly happen,
لكن مؤكد ان هذا لايحدث تمامًا
and that's because we can't just take form into account.
لأنه لايمكننا ان نعتمد على الشكل.
We have to think about function as well,
علينا ان نفكر في الوظيفة ايضًا.
and when it comes to sex,
وعندما نتحدث عن الجنس
function relates to the contributions made
الوظيفة تتعلق بمشاركة
by the gametes, or the sperm and the eggs.
الأمشاج او الحيوانات المنوية والبويضات.
And these contributions are far from equal.
وهذه المشاركة ابعد مايكون متساوية
Eggs are very expensive to make,
البويضات انتاجها غالي جدًا
so it makes sense for females to be very choosy
لذلك منطقي جدًا ان تكون الأنثى إنتقائية
about who she shares them with.
لمن ستشارك معه البويضات.
Sperm, on the other hand, is abundant and cheap,
الحيوانات المنوية من ناحية اخرى متوافرة بكثرة ورخيصة
so it makes more sense for males
إذن منطقي جدًا للذكور
to have a more-sex-is-better strategy
ان يتبنوا استراتجية افضل لممارسة الجنس
when it comes to siring members
فيما يتعلق بإنجاب أفراد
of future generations.
الأجيال القادمة
So how do animals cope
إذن كيف تتكيف الحيوانات
with these very incongruent needs between the sexes?
مع هذه الإحتياجات المتناقضة ما بين الجنسين؟
I mean, if a female doesn't choose a particular male,
اقصد اذا لم تختار الأنثى شريكًا محددًا
or if she has the ability to store sperm
او إذا كان لها المقدرة على تخزين الحيوانات المنوية
and she simply has enough,
وببساطة لديها مايكفيها
then it makes more sense for her to spend her time
إذن من المنطقي ان تقضي وقتها
doing other biologically relevant things:
في قضاء إحتياجات اخرى اكثر اهمية:
avoiding predators, taking care of offspring,
تجنب الحيوانات المفترسة, ورعاية صغارها
gathering and ingesting food.
تخزين, و إلتهام الطعام.
This is, of course, bad news for any male
هذا بالتأكيد خبر سيء لكل ذكر
who has yet to make a deposit in her sperm bank,
يحاول ان يخزن حيواناته المنوية في حسابها.
and this sets the scene for some pretty drastic strategies
هذا ايضًا يمهد المسرح لإستراتيجيات عنيفة
for successful fertilization.
لتلقيح ناجح.
This is bedbug sex,
هذا هو الجنس في قراد الفراش
and it's aptly termed traumatic insemination.
هو ايضاً يسمى بجدارة صدمة التلقيح.
Males have a spiked, barbed penis
للذكور قضيب شائك
that they literally stab into the female,
حرفيًا يقوم بطعن الأنثى
and they don't stab it anywhere near her vagina.
وهم لا يطعنون في اي مكان قريب من المهبل.
They stab it anywhere in her body,
هم يطعنونها في اي مكان في جسدها,
and the sperm simply migrates
والحيوان المنوي بكل بساطة يهاجر
through her hemolymph to her ovaries.
خلال اوعيتها الدموية إلى المبايض
If a female gets too many stab wounds,
إذا تلقت الأنثى العديد من الطعنات الدامية,
or if a stab wound happens to become infected,
او إذا التهب الجرح
she can actually die from it.
في الحقيقة ممكن ان تموت جراء ذلك
Now if you've ever been out for a nice,
الأن إذا خرجت للتنزه
peaceful walk by the lake
في اي يوم جميل قرب البحيرة
and happened to see some ducks having sex,
وحدث ان رأيت بعض البط يمارس الجنس
you've undoubtedly been alarmed,
من دون شك ستنتبه
because it looks like gang rape.
لأنه يبدو كإغتصاب جماعي
And quite frankly, that's exactly what it is.
وبصدق هذا ماهو عليه.
A group of males will grab a female,
مجموعة من الذكور سوف تخطف انثى
hold her down,
تطرحها ارضًا
and ballistically ejaculate their spiral-shaped penis
ومن خلال قضيب حلزوني الشكل يتم قذف المني
into her corkscrew-shaped vagina
إلى المهبل الذي يشبه المفتاح
over and over and over again.
تكرارًا ومرارًا
From flaccid to ejaculation in less than a second.
من تراخي إلى قذف في اقل من ثانية
Now the female actually gets the last laugh, though,
الان بإمكان الأنثى ان تضحك اخيرًا
because she can actually manipulate her posture
لأنه بإستطاعتها ان تتلاعب بوضعيتها
so as to allow the sperm of certain suitors
حتى تسمح لمني ذكر معين
better access to her ovaries.
بالوصل إلى مبايضها
Now, I like to share stories like this with my audiences
الان احب ن اشارك قصصًا مثل هذه مع المستمعين
because, yeah, we humans,
لأننا صحيح بشر
we tend to think sex, sex is fun, sex is good,
و نميل لإعتقاد ان الجنس ممتع وجيد
there's romance, and there's orgasm.
هنالك رومانسية و هنالك ايضًا شبق
But orgasm didn't actually evolve
لكن الشبق حيقيقة لم يتطور
until about 65 million years ago
حتى 65 مليون عامًا فيما مضى
with the advent of mammals.
مع ظهور الثديات
But some animals had it going on quite a bit before that.
لكن بعض الحيوانات توصلت له قبل ذلك
There are some more primitive ways
كان هنالك طرق بدائية
of pleasing one's partner.
لإمتاع الشريك
Earwig males have either
حشرة ابومقص لديها
really large penile appendages
زوائد قضيبية كبيرة
or really small ones.
او صغيرة.
It's a very simple genetically inherited trait
هي صفة وراثية بسيطة
and the males are not otherwise any different.
والذكور من ناحية اخرى غير مختلفين
Those that have long penile appendages
اولئك الذين لديهم زوائد قضيبة طويلة
are not bigger or stronger
ليست اكبر او اقوى
or otherwise any different at all.
او مختلفة بأي شكل اخر.
So going back to our biological minds, then,
إذًا بالعودة إلى عقولنا الأحيائية
we might think that females should choose
لربما ظننا ان على الإناث ان تختار
to have sex with the guys that have the shorter appendages,
ممارسة الجنس مع الذكور ذوي الزوائد القصيرة
because she can use her time for other things:
لأنه بإمكانها ان تستقل وقتها في اشياء اخرى:
avoiding predators, taking care of young,
تجنب الحيوانات المفترسة او رعاية الصغار.
finding and ingesting food.
البحث وتخزين الطعام
But biologists have repeatedly observed
لكن علماء الأحياء بصورة متكررة لاحظوا
that females choose to have sex
ان الأنثى تختار ممارسة الجنس
with the males that have the long appendages.
مع الذكر الذي لديه زوائد اطول.
Why do they do this?
لماذا يفعلن ذلك؟
Well, according to the biological literature,
حسنًا, كما في مطبوعة الأحياء,
"During copulation, the genitalia of certain males
" خلال المضاجعة الأعضاء الجنسية لبعض الذكور
may elicit more favorable female responses
بإمكانها ان تحدث ردود فعل محببة للإناث
through superior mechanical or stimulatory interaction
من خلال ميكانيكية عالية, او تفاعل تحفيزي
with the female reproductive tract."
لقناة التكاثر الأنثوية"
Mm-hm.
امم هم
These are Mexican guppies,
هذه اسماك الغابي المكسيكية,
and what you see on their upper maxilla
وما ترونه في الفك العلوي
is an outgrowth of epidermal filaments,
هو تزايد لشعيرات البشرة
and these filaments basically form
وهذه الشعيرات تكون
a fish mustache, if you will.
شارب السمكة.
Now males have been observed to prod
الان تمت ملاحظة ان الذكور ينخزون
the female's genital opening
مقدمة الأعضاء التناسلية الأنثوية
prior to copulating with her,
قبل مضاجعتها
and in what I have lovingly termed the Magnum, P.I. hypothesis,
فيما سميته بكل ود نطرية بي اي مانغوم
females are overwhelmingly more likely to be found
الإناث بأغلبية ساحقة يميلون للتواجد
with males that have these fish mustaches.
مع الذكور الذين يمتلكون هذه الشوارب
A little guppy porn for you right there.
قدمت لكم فيلم إباحي قصير لسمكة الباغي.
So we've seen very different strategies
إذن رأينا استراتيجيات مختلفة
that males are using when it comes to
يستخدمها الذكر
winning a female partner.
ليفوز بشريكة
We've seen a coercion strategy in which sexual structures are used in a forceful way
رأينا إستراتيجية الإكراه والتي تستخدم فيها الأعضاء الجنسية بقوة.
to basically make a female have sex.
لجعل الأنثى تمارس الجنس
We've also seen a titillation strategy
ايضًا رأينا استراتيجية الدغدغة
where males are actually
حيث ان الذكور
pleasing their female partners into choosing them
يرضون الإناث كي يختاروهم
as a sex partner.
كشريك
Now unfortunately, in the animal kingdom,
الان لسوء الحظ في مملكة الحيوانات
it's the coercion strategy that we see
إستراتيجية الإكراه
time and time again.
لأكثر من مرة
It's very common in many phyla,
تغلب على طوائف
from invertebrates to avian species,
الفقاريات والطيور
mammals, and, of course, even in primates.
الثديات و بالتأكيد في الثديات حتى في البدائيات
Now interestingly, there are a few mammalian species
الان مثير للإهتمام ان القليل من فصائل الثديات
in which females have evolved specialized genitalia
التي طورت إناثها اعضاء تناسلية متخصصة
that doesn't allow for sexual coercion to take place.
لاتسمح بالإكراه الجنسي
Female elephants and female hyenas
إناث الفيل و إناث الضباع
have a penile clitoris,
لديها بظر قضيبي
or an enlarged clitoral tissue that hangs externally,
او نسيج بظري متضخم يتدلى خارجيًا
much like a penis,
تمامًا كما القضيب
and in fact it's very difficult to sex these animals
وفي الحقيقة يصعب جدًا تصنيف هذه الحيوانات جنسيًا
by merely looking at their external morphology.
بمجرد النظر إلى الشكل الخارجي
So before a male can insert his penis into a female's vagina,
إذن قبل ان يدخل الذكر قضيبه إلى مهبل الأنثى
she has to take this penile clitoris
عليها ان تاخذ هذا البظر القضيب
and basically inside-out it in her own body.
وتدخله في جسدها
I mean, imagine putting a penis into another penis.
اقصد تصور ادخال قضيب إلى قضيب اخر.
It's simply not going to happen
ببساطة لايمكن ان يحدث
unless the female is on board with the action.
إلا إذا وافقت الأنثى
Now, even more interesting is the fact
والان اكثر إثارة للإهتمام حقيقة
that elephant and hyena societies
ان مجتمعات الفيلة والضباع
are entirely matriarchal:
مجتمعات انثوية بالكلية
they're run by females, groups of females,
تديرها مجموعات من الإناث
sisters, aunts and offspring,
اخوات, خالات, وصغار
and when young males attain sexual maturity,
وعندما يصل الصغار الذكور إلى النضج
they're turfed out of the group.
يتم طردهم خارج المجموعة
In hyena societies, adult males
في مجتمعات الضباع، الذكر البالغ
are actually the lowest on the social scale.
له ادنى ترتيب في المقياس الإجتماعي
They can take part in a kill only after
بإمكانه ان يقتاد على الفريسة
everybody else, including the offspring.
بعد ان يقتاد كل شخص بما فيهم الصغار.
So it seems that when you take the penis power
إذن عندما تأخذ سلطة القضيب
away from a male,
من الذكر
you take away all the social power he has.
انت تأخذ مكانته الإجتماعية
So what are my take-home messages from my talk today?
إذن ما الرسائل التي ستاخذونها معكم من هذا الحديث؟
Well, sex is just so much more
حسنًا, الجنس اكثر
than insert part A into slot B
من إدخال أ في ب
and hope that the offspring run around everywhere.
و تمني ان ينتشر الصغار في كل مكان
The sexual strategies and reproductive structures
الإستراتيجيات الجنسية و الأعضاء التناسلية
that we see in the animal kingdom basically
التي نراها في مملكة الحيوان
dictate how males and females will react to each other,
حددت كيف سيتفاعل الذكور والإناث مع بعضهم
which then dictates how populations and societies
والذي بدوره يحدد عدد السكان والمجتمعات
form and evolve.
التي تطورت
So it may not be surprising to any of you
إذن لربما ليست مفاجأة لأي احد منكم
that animals, including ourselves,
ان الحيوانات بما فيها فصيلتنا
spend a good amount of time thinking about sex,
تستغرق وقت طويل في التفكير في الجنس
but what might surprise you is the extent to which
لكن ما سيفاجئكم مدى
so many other aspects of their lives and our lives
النواحي من حياتهم و حياتنا
are influenced by it.
التي تتأثر به.
So thank you, and happy daydreaming.
إذن شكرًا لكم, وأحلام يقظة سعيدة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)